As our first function,
في الدالة الأولى،
we'll write a function that calculates the volume of a cylinder.
سنكتب دالة تحسب حجم اسطوانة.
The formula for this is the cylinder's height,
المعادلة لهذا هي طول الاسطوانة
multiplied by the square of its radius, multiplied by pi.
مضروباً في مربع نصف قطره مضروباً في "باي".
Here's what that formula looks like when defined in a function called cylinder volume.
هكذا تبدو المعادلة عند تعريفها في دالة تسمى cylinder_volume.
After defining the cylinder volume function,
بعد تعريف دالة حجم الاسطوانة،
we can use it like this.
يمكننا استخدامها هكذا.
This value is the volume of a cylinder 10 inches tall with a radius of three inches.
هذه القيمة هي حجم اسطوانة طولها 10 إنشات ونصف قطرها 3 إنشات.
Let's see how this works behind the scenes.
لنرى كيف يعمل هذا خلف الكواليس.
A function definition includes several important parts.
يتضمن تعريف الدالة عدة أجزاء مهمة.
First, let's look at the function header.
أولاً، لننظر إلى عنوان الدالة.
Defining a function always starts with
يبدأ تعريف الدالة دائماً
the def keyword to indicate that the code that follows is a function definition,
بكلمة def للإشارة إلى أن الكود الذي يتبعها هو تعريف لدالة،
and ends with a colon.
وينتهي بنقطتين رأسيتين.
Following def is the name of the function.
يتبع كلمة def اسم الدالة.
In this case, cylinder_volume.
وهو في هذه الحالة، cylinder_volume.
This needs to be a one word with no gaps.
يجب أن يكون هذا الاسم كلمة واحدة بدون مسافات.
That's why this has an underscore.
لهذا السبب لديها شرطة سفلية، "_".
The rules for function names are the same as those for variable names.
قوانين تسمية الدوال هي نفسها قوانين تسمية المتغيّرات.
If you need a reminder on this,
إذا أردتم تذكر ذلك،
see the text below this video.
فانظروا إلى النص أسفل هذا الفيديو.
After the function name are parentheses that
يأتي بعد اسم الدالة القوسان
includes the arguments that the function expects, separated by commas.
اللذان يحتويان على الوسيطات التي تتوقعها الدالة، مفصولة عن بعضها بالفواصل.
These arguments are values that are passed in as inputs
هذه الوسيطات هي قيم يتم تمريرها كمدخلات
when the function is called and are used in this body.
عند استدعاء الدالة ويتم استخدامها داخل هذه الكتلة.
If you write a function that doesn't take arguments,
إذا كتبتم دالة لا تأخذ الوسيطات،
then just leave these parentheses empty.
فاتركوا هذين القوسين فارغين فحسب.
Here is an example of a function that takes no arguments.
هذا مثال على دالة لا تأخذ أية وسيطات.
In this case, there is no input data we want to work with in the body of the function,
في هذه الحالة، لا وجود لأي بيانات مدخلة للتعامل معها في كتلة الدالة،
so no arguments are necessary.
فلا داعٍ لأية وسيطات.
Next, let's discuss the body of a function.
والآن لنتناول كتلة الدالة.
The body of the function is indented after
تترك مسافة بادئة أكبر من السطر السابق لكتلة الدالة بعد العنوان
Within this body, we can refer to the argument variables and define new variables.
داخل هذه الكتلة، يمكننا الإشارة إلى المتغيّرات الوسيطة وتعريف متغيّرات جديدة.
The pi variable that we define here is a local variable.
متغيّر pi الذي عرّفناه هنا هو متغيّر محلي.
Meaning; it can only be used within the body of this function.
يعني أنه يمكن استخدامه ضمن كتلة هذه الدالة فقط.
Attempting to access this variable outside the function isn't possible.
محاولة الوصول إلى هذا المتغيّر من خارج هذه الدالة غير ممكن.
This is due to what is called variable scope,
وهذا بسبب ما يُسمى بنطاق المتغيّر،
which determines which variables you have access to in Python.
وهو يحدد أي متغيّرات يمكنك الوصول إليها في لغة Python.
We'll discuss this in detail later in the lesson.
سنناقش ذلك بتفصيل أكبر في وقت لاحق في الدرس.
Often, the body of a function will include
عادة ما تضم كتلة الدالة
this return key word which is used to
كلمة return هذه والتي تُستخدم
give back an output value when the function is called.
لإرجاع قيمة مخرجة عند استدعاء الدالة.
The value of the expression that follows return is the output of the function.
وقيمة العبارة التي تتبع كلمة return هي نتيجة الدالة.
In this example, we return the value evaluated from
في هذا المثال، نُرجع القيمة
this formula for the volume of a cylinder.
التي نتجت من معادلة حجم الاسطوانة هذه.
Rather than returning the value as it is calculated,
بدلاً من إرجاع القيمة بينما يتم حسابها،
an alternative technique would be to calculate the volume earlier in
هناك طريقة بديلة بحساب الحجم مسبقاً
the function body and then store it in a variable named volume.
في كتلة الدالة ثم تخزينه في متغيّر يسمى volume.
In this case, we would return volume like this.
في هذه الحالة، نرجع الحجم هكذا.
Functions like this can be imagined as little machines that take
يمكن تخيّل دوال كهذه كآلات صغيرة
inputs or arguments and process them into output or return values.
تأخذ المدخلات أو الوسيطات وتعالجها لتصبح مخرجات أو قيم مرجعة.
This is a good image but it's incomplete.
هذا تصوّر حسن لكنه ليس كاملاً.
Some functions like print don't return anything at all.
بعض الدوال مثل print لا ترجع شيئاً على الإطلاق.
Print displays text on the output window but as we see here,
دائماً تعرض print نصاً على نافذة المخرجات، لكن كما نرى هنا،
the value it returns is none.
قيمة الحجم المرجعة هي لا شيء، "None".
None is when a function will return by
None هو ما ترجعه الدالة بشكل افتراضي
The difference between print and return is often confused.
عادة ما يحدث خلط في التفريق بين print وreturn.
Print provides output to the console while return provides
تعطي print مخرجات إلى وحدة التحكم بينما تعطي return
the value that you can store and work with and code later.
قيمة يمكن تخزينها والعمل بها وكتابة كود لها لاحقاً.
You'll get some practice with this in the quizzes that follow.
ستحصلون على بعض التدريب على هذا خلال الاختبارات التالية.
It's not necessary that every function has a return statement.
لا يشترط أن تمتلك كل دالة عبارة return.
Notice this function, print_greeting,
لاحظوا أن هذه الدالة، print_greeting،
doesn't have a return statement,
لا تملك لها عبارة return،
but it's still a valid function.
لكنها لا تزال دالة صحيحة.